Guide to the Eclipse Enterprises Trading Cards Collection, 1989-1993 RL.11186
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Eclipse Enterprises trading cards collection
1989-1993
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Eclipse Comics
RL.11186
0.5 Linear Feet
Complete group of ten trading card sets on social and political topics created by California company Eclipse Enterprises, dating 1989-1993.
Biographical / Historical
Eclipse Enterprises, also known as Eclipse Comics, was an independent American comic book publisher during the 1980s and early 1990s. In 1978, it published the first graphic novel intended for specialty comic stores; it also was one of the first companies to offer royalties and creator ownership of rights. It was also one of the early comic book publishers to produce trading cards.
Eclipse Enterprises was founded by brothers Jan and Dean Mullaney in 1977; it eventually settled and operated in Sonoma County, California. Due to the controversial products it distributed (which led to several lawsuits), as well as a devestating flood in 1986, Eclipse suffered ongoing financial hardships and eventually ceased operations in 1994. The owners filed for bankruptcy in 1995.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Eclipse Enterprises Trading Cards Collection was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2016.
Collection Overview
Collection contains the complete run of non-sports, non-fiction boxed trading card sets produced by Eclipse Enterprises between 1989 and 1993. Titles include: Rotten to the Core: The Best and Worst of New York City's Politics; Bush League Trading Cards; Friendly Dictators Trading Cards, Featuring 36 of America's Most Embarrassing Allies; The Rock Bottom Awards: The Best and Worst in Bad Taste; Coup D'Etat: The Assassination of John F. Kennedy; Foul Ball Trading Cards: Baseball's Greatest Scandals, Scoundrels, and Screw-Ups; Savings and Loan Scandal Trading Cards; Drug Wars Trading Cards: The Straight Dope on America's Dirtiest Deals; Iran-Contra Scandal Trading Cards, Featuring the Secret Team; and AIDS Awareness Trading Cards.
AIDS (Disease) -- United States -- Prevention -- Pictorial works; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963 -- Death and burial; Iran -- Foreign relations -- United States; Drug control -- United States; Dictatorship -- Latin America -- History -- 20th century; United States -- Foreign relations -- 1945-; Popular culture -- New York (State) -- New York; Baseball -- United States; Comic cards; Bush, George, 1924-; Eclipse Comics; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963
- AIDS Awareness Trading Cards, 1993 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Text: Perry Gaskill, William Livingstone, Catherine Yronwode, Althaea Yronwode. Illustrations: Greg Loudon, Charles Hiscock. Includes a sample package with condom.
- Bush League Trading Cards, 1989 (Box 1)
  Editor: Catherine Yronwode. Writer: Paul Brancato. Art: Salim Yaqub.
- Coup D'Etat: The Assassination of John F. Kennedy Trading Cards, 1990 (Box 1)
  Editor: Catherine Yronwode. Text: Paul Brancato. Art: Bill Sienkiewicz.
- Drug Wars Trading Cards: The Straight Dope on America's Dirtiest Deals, 1991 (Box 1)
  Editor: Catherine Yronwode. Writers: Paul Brancato and Bob Callahan. Art: Salib Yaqub.
- Foul Ball Trading Cards: Baseball's Greatest Scandals, Scoundrels, and Screw-Ups, 1991 (Box 1)
  Editor: Catherine Yronwode. Text: Gary Cohen. Art: William Cone.
- Friendly Dictators Trading Cards: Featuring 36 of America's Most Embarrassing Allies, 1989 (Box 1)
  Editor: Catherine Yronwode. Writers: Dennis Bernstein and Laura Sydell. Art: Bill Sienkiewicz.
- Iran-Contra Scandal Trading Cards, Featuring the Secret Team, undated (Box 1)
- The Comedy Channel presents the Rock Bottom Awards: The Best and Worst in Bad Taste, 1990 (Box 1)
  Editor: Catherine Yronwode. Writer: Peggy Gordon. Art: Bill Sienkiewicz.
- Rotten to the Core Trading Cards: The Best and Worst of New York City's Politics, 1989 (Box 1)
  Editor: Catherine Yronwode. Writers: Peggy Gordon and Dean Mullaney. Artists: Rick Bryant and George Kochell.
- Savings and Loan Scandal Trading Cards, 1991 (Box 1)
  Editor: Catherine Yronwode. Writers: Dennis Bernstein and Laura Sydell. Artist: Stewart Stanyard. Whip: Paul Brancato.